linkedin.com/in/KyleTurchik

Kyle Turchik

Full Portfolio: kturchik.github.io

kturchik@sbcglobal.net

(951) 316-1112

Associate Software Engineer

Inspired and dynamic programmer with 3 years of experience in game development for PC, web, and mobile. Proven leader driven by collaboration with multidisciplinary teams. Recognized for being versatile, outgoing, creative, and meticulous. Seeking a challenging entry-level role in tools, UI, graphics, or gameplay programming.

EXPERIENCE

ARVADA LABS | R&D Engineer (tiny.cc/arvadalabs)

01/2018 - Present

Implementing core gameplay feature prototypes using Unity for an augmented reality multiplayer card game.

- ♦ Improving performance and memory efficiency on mobile devices by profiling and optimizing code base.
- Streamlining integration of assets by acting as main coordinator between teams of artists and engineers.
- ♦ Created custom shaders to mask and project objects for seamless portal effects.

BLIZZARD ENTERTAINMENT | Software Engineer Intern

06/2017 - 09/2017

Developed a rich single-page web application using WebGL with React and Node.js.

- ♦ Created a 3D rendered display of large real-time data streams from protobuf websockets.
- ♦ Solved a critical framerate issue, using object pooling and object-oriented patterns with WebGL.
- Enhanced the project by developing a keystone feature, outside the initial scope, during a hackathon.
- ♦ Implemented detailed UX design and animation specifications with Javascript and CSS.
- ♦ Collaborated directly with artists, program managers, and fellow engineers in an Agile/Scrum environment, utilizing JIRA and Confluence to coordinate tasks, Jenkins for CI/CD, and Git for code sharing and reviews.

GOOGLE APPLIED CS PROGRAM | Student Programmer (a.co/appliedcsskills)

04/2016 - 06/2016

Created Android applications with Java and Android Studio as part of a pilot program for a select group of students that reinforces concepts from data structures and algorithms, as well as artificial intelligence.

PROJECTS & AWARDS

Augmented Realms | Independent Team Project

12/2017 - Present

Developing, with Unity and C#, the world building tools, RPG gameplay mechanics, UI, and augmented reality functionality using Vuforia for a multiplayer mobile app designed to enhance tabletop RPG gaming.

inVRasion | Independent Team Project

09/2017 - Present

Building, with Unity and C#, the UI, AI, player movement, and weapon mechanics for an asymmetric multiplayer virtual reality FPS game in development for HTC Vive and PlayStation VR devices.

Elemental Fury | 3RD Place Overall - BeachHacks

04/2017

Implemented, with Unity and C#, the client-side network using Photon Unity Networking, player controls, and spell mechanics for a multiplayer virtual reality game using networked HTC Vive devices.

Battle of the Bards | 2ND Place Overall & Best Game - HackPoly

02/2017

Created the UI, turn-based mechanics, procedural audio, and particle systems for an RPG/rhythm game.

LEADERSHIP

Student Game Developer Alliance | Founder, Committee Chair (sada.io)

02/2017 - Present

Founded the largest student-organized game development association in California dedicated to inspiring and facilitating game development for 200+ students from 9 universities by organizing educational events.

Cal Poly Pomona Game Design & Development Club | President

03/2016 - 06/2017

Lead a new student club focused on preparing students for game industry careers, mentoring 60+ members by hosting workshops and coordinating large studio-like teams of multidisciplinary students to develop games.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: (3 years) C# ♦ C++ ♦ Java (1 year) JavaScript ♦ Python ♦ Lua ♦ HTML/CSS

Tools: Unity ♦ GIT ♦ Visual Studio ♦ Xcode ♦ Android Studio ♦ .NET ♦ WPF/WinForms ♦ OpenGL ♦ JIRA

Key Concepts: Game Development ♦ Mobile (Android/iOS) ♦ 3D Graphics/Math ♦ Memory Management

♦ Object-Oriented Programming ♦ UI Implementation ♦ Computer Networks ♦ AR/VR ♦ Agile/Scrum

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, CA

Cum Laude (Major GPA: 3.6) (Graduation: December 2017)